The Google DeepMind team has been
absolutely on fire recently, rolling out
with major enhancements across all of
its product lines. Take Google AI Studio
for example. It's practically a fully
free AI coding agent that you can access
right now that lets you build and
generate any AI app instantly connected
to the Gemini SDK. This is just one of
many AI coding tools Google is pushing
to completely supercharge your developer
workflow. But here's the bigger picture.
It looks like the Google Deep Mind team
is preparing all their tools for
something huge. The launch of their
newest state-of-the-art model, Gemini
3.0, which could be releasing this week.
And to support it, they have been
rapidly enhancing all their tools like
Google Code Assist, which is adding a
brand new Asia mode that can transform
it into a fully autonomous AI coding
agent that's capable of practically
doing anything for you right inside your
IDE, whether it's VS Code, Cursor, or
even Jet Brains. And the wildest part is
it's fully free. Think of it as having
client or root code built into Google's
ecosystem, but even more deeply
integrated. But essentially, the agent
mode in Google's Gemini code assist is a
new feature that turns it into a
collaborative autonomous coding agent
inside your ID. Instead of just writing
step-by-step changes yourself, you can
simply describe your goal, and Gemini
generates a detailed plan. It can handle
multi-step edits, use full project
context, and integrate with tools while
keeping you in control. It also has the
ability to run terminalbased commands,
streamline all the edits live in action,
and exactly like how PL would do it.
Before we get started, I just want to
mention that you should definitely go
ahead and subscribe to the world of AI
newsletter. I'm constantly posting
different newsletters on a weekly basis.
So this is where you can easily get
up-to-date knowledge about what is
happening in the AI space. So definitely
go ahead and subscribe as this is
completely for free. But they also
introduced a lot of improvements since
they initially released agent mode. It's
not something that's super new, but they
have improved a lot of functionalities
of it like the ability to add code
snippets into the chat context. They're
actually removing the code assist tools
because they're going to keep agent mode
as the main function for that extension.
There's new abilities like next edit
predictions. It is also something that
has inline diffs which is generally
available and a lot of other things
which we'll take a look at throughout
today's video. But one of the main
issues that we saw with coticus before
was its limits. But now they have
increased higher limits on the free tier
where you can access the Gemini 2.5 Pro.
But if you're looking to get even more
limits, you can obviously subscribe to
their Gemini Pro plans, which I believe
is something that is worth it cuz you
can access a lot of different suite of
tools a part of Google. Now, if you're
looking to get started, it's super
simple. Head over to the Gemini Code
Assist website, which I'll leave a link
to in the description below. Click on
try now and you can easily install it
for VS code or for Jet Brains. It's
essentially extension and I'm going to
be installing it in VS Code. So you can
simply click on install and you can open
up the Visual Studio Code marketplace.
Now once it has opened up you can click
on install and then it should show up
within the lefthand panel over here.
Then you can simply go ahead and click
on the Gemini Code Assist extension. And
this is where you're going to be
prompted to either sign in or create an
account with Google, which is completely
for free. After signing in, you're going
to be then greeted with this panel over
here. And this is where you can now work
with the agent mode. You can essentially
chat with it like you would with client
where you can send in any natural
language prompt attach various contexts
whether that's a full-on codebase and
make sure you have agent mode enabled to
execute any task like creating me a time
management app. You can then send in
this prompt and it's going to be able to
execute it autonomously using the Gemini
2.5 Pro. And you can see it is going to
start off by first using its reasoning
capabilities to plan out how it's going
to execute this task like creating the
front end, the back end as well as the
styling. And you can then adjust the
plan. And you can see right here that it
is working on using a shell command
where it's going to first ask you if you
can run it or not. You can set this on
always run MPX, but I wouldn't always
recommend that. So, just simply just
approve it by clicking on run and then
it will execute the task of creating the
React app. The agent mode also showcases
live streaming, which is a way for you
to visualize the code being generated
live in action. There's also diff
changes that it will also show. You can
accept it and stay in control as it
generates your app. Let's say if there's
a code block that you think needs more
manual intervention, you can then click
edit and you can actually edit certain
components directly within your editor,
which is perfect. And there we go. We
have our time management app where we
can track our tasks as well as manage
our time efficiently. You can see that
it did a pretty fast job in creating
this app that has actually a lot of
features. talks about the
recommendations as to how you can
improve your time management skills, the
productivity insights. It gives you a
score on all of these different metrics
like the average times per weeks you
have, task completed, estimation,
accuracy, etc. But there's a lot of
different features that added
animations, different placeholders.
There's also dark mode, which is good to
see. And then we can add in any of our
task over here or visualize them and
then add a task over here. There's
actually a timer and there's also a data
management where you can back up your
data. I'm not too sure if this actually
works or not, but this is pretty good to
see because it added as many features as
possible. Also focus on creating a
responsive app for me, which it looks
pretty good. You also have inline
suggestions as well as automated code
directly within the code editor. So you
can actually add a certain section of
the code back into the code panel so
Gemini could actually focus on it with
the code assist like generating code,
generating unit test and then pinning
the section to the current chat prompt
or adding the file to Gemini context.
This is actually a new feature and
essentially this is where you can
reference certain sections of your code
directly within the panel so it's easier
for it to understand what you're talking
about. So if there's like a certain
section of code that you need help with,
you can add it as context and the Gemini
agent will be able to actually help you
on that specific lines of code. But
having a free client that allows you to
use something like the Gemini 2.5 Pro is
just impressive cuz you can easily use
the state-of-the-art model to rapidly
build anything as a smart coding agent
like you would with kilo code line or
even with root code. This is something
that is fully free and I know there's
still a lot of features left to be added
to it, but I think over time they'll
keep improving it and they'll keep
making this a featurerich AI tool. If
you like this video and would love to
support the channel, you can consider
donating to my channel through the super
thanks option below. Or you can consider
joining our private Discord where you
can access multiple subscriptions to
different AI tools for free on a monthly
basis, plus daily AI news and exclusive
content, plus a lot more. But that's
basically it, guys, for this new Gemini
code assist agent mode feature. I'll
leave all these links in the description
below so that you can easily get
started. There's a couple things that I
didn't actually mention like MCPS as
well as how you can use the next edit
prediction feature. So, I'll leave these
links so that you can get a better idea
as to what you can do with this new
agent mode update. But with that
thought, guys, thank you guys so much
for watching. I hope you enjoyed today's
video. Make sure you subscribe to the
second channel if you haven't already.
Join the newsletter, join our private
Discord, follow me on Twitter, and
lastly, make sure you guys subscribe,
turn on notification bell, like this
video, and please take a look at our
previous videos because there's a lot of
content that you'll truly benefit from.
But with that thought, guys, have an
amazing day. Spread positivity, and I'll
see you guys really shortly. is off.